# **CURRICULAM VITAE**

#### JYOTSNA KUMBHARE

Phone: +91-9860145718 (India) E-mail: jyotsna@bluecrosslabs.com Personal: jyotsnakumbhare@gmail.com

DOB: 18<sup>th</sup> Feb 1981

### **EXPERIENCE SUMMARY**

A Computer professional with 17 years of total IT experience, out of which 15 years in SAP R/3 and ECC 6.0, (Major in Technical ABAP/4 and Minor in Functional modules a ratio of 65:35). For the last seven years, was working primarily on the implementation and support of SAP R/3 and ECC 6.0.

Currently working with BLUE CROSS LABS Ltd as a SAP Technical Consultant from 1<sup>st</sup> April 2008. My primary focus is on technical development and consultant level support to my organization.

Worked with PAC Computers Ltd, Mumbai as a SAP Technical Consultant from 1<sup>st</sup> Feb 2007 to 30<sup>th</sup> March 2008.

Worked with CPS Computers, in Mumbai as a faculty member for software languages like C, C++, JAVA, Dot Net and Oracle SQL, PL/SQL, working duration 1<sup>st</sup> April 2006 to 30<sup>th</sup> Oct 2006.

Worked with PIX Transmission Ltd, Nagpur as a Trainee Engineer from 1<sup>st</sup> December 2004 to 30<sup>th</sup> November 2005.

#### IT KNOWLEDGE

II KNOWLEDGE			
<b>Operating Systems:</b>	Windows 2010		
<b>Programming Languages:</b>	: ABAP-4 (sound proficiency in Reports, SAP Scripts, Smart forms,		
	Module pools, Function modules, Enhancement techniques) C, C++.		
Databases:	Oracle9i, MS Access		
ERP:	SAP (R/3 4.7 E and ECC 6.0)		
Technologies in SAP R/3:	LSMW, BDC (Data migration with flat Files), EDI / IDOC, Work		
	Flow, Exposure in Transport request management, user authorizations		
	maintenance, Profile maintenance, SAP BW exposure		
Designing:	Form Painter and Menu Painter		
<b>Testing Tools:</b>	CATT in SAP R/3		
Functional Area:	Sales and Distribution, FI/CO, MM, QM and HR in SAP		

#### PERSONAL STRENGTH

Strong understanding in conversion of functional requirement into technical form Fast learner with good communication skill, and also enjoys working in a team.

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Computer Technology BE (4 years degree course) in Computer Engineering from Priyadarshini College of Engineering, Nagpur, Nagpur University, Maharashtra. India.

# **SPECIAL TRAINING UNDERGONE**

ABAP/4 – Three months training done at Beyond Logics, Mumbai Attended BIW Training given by Spectrasoft, Chennai, sponsored by BLUECROSS LABORATORIES LTD,NASIK.

# SAP ABAP SKILLS

**Reporting:** Simple and Interactive Reports, ALV Grid, and ALV using Classes.

**Dialog Programming**: Module Pool Programming, Function Module and Function Groups.

**SAP Forms:** *SAP Script, Smart Forms& Adobe forms for Layout designing.* 

**Data Upload:** Batch Data Communication.

Data Dictionary: Tables, Data Element, Domains, Search Help and Search Help Exits.

**Enhancements:** *BADI*, *IDocs and Spool Generation*. **Cross Application:** *Good knowledge of BAPI and RFC*.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE DETAILS**

**1.** BLUE CROSS LABS Ltd, Nasik as a SAP Technical Consultant from 1<sup>st</sup> April 2008 to till date. <u>SAP Version</u>: SAP (R/3 4.7 E and ECC 6.0)

BLUE CROSS LABS Ltd is a pharmastitual company having a turnover of 1000 crores, it has corporate office in Mumbai and factories at Nashk and Goa .In 4.7 Version of SAP It has implemented FI/CO, MM, PP, DISTRIBUTION PM, QM/QC Modules. Now it is going for ECC 6.0 with additional HR module and SALES with Added functionality, the GO-Live date on 1<sup>st</sup> July 2010.

<u>Role & Responsibility:</u> In this company my role is to cater the Technical and Functional Issues required as per the business needs, I have efficiently developed the reports for all modules (FI/CO, MM, PP, SD PM, QM/QC & HR)

- Developed Z report for Excise Transaction related to RG1
- Developed a report for TDS and With-holding Tax amount
- Developed report on Taxation for company Tax filing
- Developed a synchronized report for SAP stock and Physical stock for reconciling the stock accurately
- Developed reports for Credit memo and debit memo
- Developed a program for Invoice of Scrap Materials
- Developed some reports using Authorization Objects
- Developed BDC program to upload the data
- Applied SAP notes to avoid stock discrepancy.
- Develop a Check printing program for Accounts

- Efficiently used BADI and User Exits whenever required
- Enhance TCODE MB0A to auto copy expiry date & manufacturing date of the product using BADI.
- Enhance TCODE FB60 to check TDS credit limit of Vendor using BADI.
- Enhance TCODE VKM3 to check overdue of customer using Implicit enhancement technique etc.....
- Worked extensively on Enhancement techniques like User Exits and BADIs (Business AddIns).
- Worked extensively on Performance Analysis of SAP programs using SAP standard tools such as Runtime analysis and SQL Trace.
- Develop Data Dictionary Objects such as Tables, Match Codes, Data elements, Domains, Structures, Views, Lock Objects and Search Helps.
- Developed QMS module in SAP (Change Control & Deviation).
- Lead CSV project & executed it as per Pharma guidelines.
- Handling Technical & Functional issues, regular functional support for all SAP users in SAP SD, FI, QM, PP & HR module..

# **2.** PAC Computers Ltd, Mumbai as a SAP Technical Consultant from 1<sup>st</sup> Feb 2007 to 30<sup>th</sup> March 2008.

PAC Computers Ltd is a middle level company who has a base in Mumbai and Hyderabad, which is engage in Implementations of SAP B1(business one)on its own and SAP R/3 and ECC Suit through sub-contracting route by tie-up with big organizations

I was one of the team member for implementation of SAP at Gupta Synthetics Ltd, Wapi Gujarat

Some of the Objects developed for Gupta Synthetics Ltd are

- Written a BDC program for G/L account which will upload the G/L accounts from legacy system to SAP
- Designed Smart form to modify layout set for Invoice, inserted company logo and address ad standard text
- Developed the sales order input report for comparison of Committed Vs Actual orders.
- Developed dispatch report ZDESP which will contain the batch wise delivery details.
- Developed a monthly report of material movements of fast moving stocks and the requirement of raw materials for these fast moving materials.

#### **3**. CPS Computers

Worked with CPS Computers, in Mumbai as a faculty member for software languages like C, C++, JAVA, Dot Net and Oracle SQL, PL/SQL, working duration 1<sup>st</sup> April 2006 to 30<sup>th</sup> Oct 2006

#### 4. PIX Transmission Ltd

Worked with PIX Transmission Ltd, Nagpur as a Trainee Engineer in EDP department from 1<sup>st</sup> December 2004 to 30<sup>th</sup> November 2005.

PIX Transmission Ltd is a company located in MIDC area Nagpur, which is in the manufacturing of Different types of V- Belts, in this company I have worked as a programmer in the EDP dept for inhouse development of Inventory management system, for this I have developed a system for production plan about the product to be produced during the particular month, also the bills of material, containing the item and the quantity required to produce a particular product in a particular month

Item shortage forecasting of the quantity that has to be produced by taking into account the current stock, the designing and coding of the program is done by employing a top-down approach and SDLC standards, also the structural and functional testing were performed

# **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION**

Degree/Certificate	University/Institute	Percentage	Year
B.E Computer Tech	P.C.E &A College	59	April 2004
H.S.C	J.B College	67	March 1998
S.S.C	N.E.H.S School	58	March 1996